FATIH CICEK

CURRICULUM VITAE



ABOUT ME

Expert in economics and the humanities with multiple years of work experience in project and institutional management. Web Developer. Keen interest in the Middle East, international cooperation and comparative intellectual history. Experienced in organizing and managing events.

+49 (0) 174 25 25 25 1 | cicekfatih@outlook.de | Aroser Allee 121, 13407 Berlin

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth: 20.01.1992 Nationality: German

CAREER EXPERIENCE

October 2021 - present | Berlin Jobcoach / Social Education Worker, Gbb mbH

• Supporting adults in arranging work placements and matching them with suitable positions

January 2019 - September 2020 | Berlin Advisor on Radicalisation prevention Violence Prevention Network e.V.

- Developed interdisciplinary approaches to prevent radicalization online
- Analysis of discourses of extremist groups

June - November 2018 | Dortmund Integration Courses, Grone Bildungszentren

 Worked with refugees, migrants and socially disadvantaged members of the public

August 2015 - September 2016 | Castrop-R. Founder and CEO, Lerngipfel e.V.

- Responsible for budget controls and human resource management
- Liaised with public authorities and lodged applications for permits

August - September 2012 | Istanbul Work experience, Turkish Review

- Worked within the editorial department for International Relations and Conflict Resolution.
- Research Assistant

EDUCATION

April-October 2021 | Berlin Full Stack Web Development Program Career Foundry GmbH

September 2016 - December 2017 | Cairo Arabic Language

Lesanularab, Language Center for Modern Standard Arabic

- Completed C1 Level, certified by the Egyptian Department of Education & Foreign Ministry
- Media Arabic

2014 - 2015 | London MA Religion in Global Politics SOAS, University of London

- High Merit (65) degree within the top 15%
- Modern Trends in Islam, Religion in Global Politics, Human Rights and Islamic Law, Politics of Resistance in the Middle East, Conflicts Rights and Justice.
- Politics and Society of the Middle East

August - September 2015 | Cairo Research Stay University of Cairo

2010 - 2014 | Bochum BSc Management & Economics Ruhr-Universität Bochum

FATIH CICEK

IT SKILLS

Social Media

 Professional experience managing Facebook, Instagram and Twitter accounts

Film production and Coding

- Good knowledge of Final Cut Pro X
- HTML, CSS, Javascript
- Experience with Python

Microsoft Office Suite

 Extensive skills in Microsoft Word, Excel, powerPoint and Outlook, applying these on a daily basis

Operating Systems

 Longstanding experience with Windows PC and Mac OS

INTERESTS

- Passionate about boxing, traveling and playing team sports
- Keen interest in exploring new cultures and cuisines
- Oud player

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

2014 - 2015 | London

Founder and President of Turkish Society

- Founded the Turkish Society at university, engaging students to participate in various events and positions within the society
- Responsible for overall work of the society
- Organised academic events

2012 - 2013

Zahnräder Netzwerk

- Developed a new PR strategy with content
- Responsible for budget, applications for subsidies, fundraising, sponsoring

2011 - 2012 | Berlin

Memeber of the Young Islam Conference

Mercator-Foundation, Humboldt-Universität Berlin

2011 - 2014 | Brühl

Invited Member of the Future Forum Islam

Federal Agency for Civic Education

LANGUAGE SKILLS

German	
Turkish	
English	
Arabic - C2	
French - A2	

BERLIN, FEBRUARY 1, 2022

2/2